A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller, Sr. papers FA002
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Financial materials, 1800-1915; F
  - Ledgers, Journals and Cash Books, 1841-1938; F.1
    - Alphabetical Index, Areas of the board, corners and spine are damaged exposing crash. Paste downs are intact. Flyleafs' are torn and separating along bindings and gutters. Pages are loose and detached from crash. (Box 188)
      Burr's Combination Index. Inside Book Plate - Burr's Ledger Index, No. 50.
    - Bills Receivable and Bills Payable, 1869 February-1883 April; Areas of the board are worn and faded. Spine is damaged with cracking along joints and exposing crash. Paste downs are intact. Flyleafs' are torn and separating along bindings and gutters. Pages are intact and secure. (Box 189)
      Inside Book Plate - Sanford and Company
    - Monies Receivable and Payable, 1892-1895; Areas of the board, corners and spine are worn, frayed and torn. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and stretched. Pages are intact and secure. (Box 190)
      Inside Book Plate - Standard Oil Co. Order No. 18088. Wallace D. Barkley, Manufacturer, No. 35321
    - General Balance Sheets 1915, 1915-1916; Pages are yellowing with frayed and torn edges. (Box 191)
      Inside Book Plate - I-P Ring Binder, No. 169199, Irving-Pitt Mfr. Co.
    - General Balance Sheets 1915-1916, 1915 March-1916 September; Pages are yellowing with frayed and torn edges. (Box 192)
    - Land Contracts, 1873-1874; Areas of the board, corners and edges are worn, frayed and torn. Spine is missing with crash exposed. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. Location unknown. (Box 193)
      Inside Book Plate - Sanford and Company, Cleveland, OH
    - Map of Real Estate, Cleveland, pre-1891, Areas of the board, corners and joints are worn, frayed and torn. Spine is worn and damaged with crash exposed. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. Location unknown. (Box 194)
    - JDR Account Book, "A", 1889-1893; Areas of the board, corners and joints are worn, frayed and torn. Spine is missing. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact but damaged. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 195)
      Inside Book Plate - Standard Oil Co. of New York, No. 11677
    - JDR Account Book, "B", 1897-1905; Areas of the board, corners and joints are worn, frayed and torn. Spine is worn and damaged. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact but damaged. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 196)
      Inside Book Plate - Standard Oil Co. of New York, No. 38637. Hall's Letter Books, No. 38637, Series No. 877
    - JDR Account Book, "C", 1898-1903; Areas of the board, corners and joints are worn, frayed and torn. Spine is worn and damaged. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact but damaged. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 197)
      Inside Book Plate - Standard Oil Co. of New York, No. 18897, Edward V. Brokaw, No. 36658
    - JDR Account Book, "D", 1902-1914; Areas of the board, corners and joints are worn, frayed and torn. Spine is worn and damaged. Paste downs and flyleafs' are torn along gutter and detached. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 198)
      Inside Book Plate - Edward V. Brokaw and Bro.
    - JDR Account Book, Leather Manufacturer's National Bank, 1885-1886; Areas of the board, corners and spine are worn, frayed and torn. Spine is separating from joints. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 199)
      Inside Book Plate - Short and Forman, Cleveland, OH
    - JDR Account Book, Leather Manufacturer's National Bank, 1891-1893; Areas of the board, corners and spine are worn, frayed and torn. Spine is separating from joints. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 200)
    - JDR Account Book, Euclid Ave. National Bank, 1886; Areas of the board, corners and spine are worn and frayed. Spine is cracking along joints. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 201)
      Inside Book Plate - Short and Forman, Cleveland, OH, No. 79307
    - Rents and Insurance, 1885-1886; Areas of board and spine edges and corners are worn and frayed. Spine is partially detached exposing crash, hinges, stitching and cracked joints. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 202)
      Inside Book Plate - Short and Forman, Cleveland, OH, No. 63004
    - Rents and Insurance, 1887-1888; Areas of board and spine edges and corners are worn and frayed. Spine is partially detached exposing crash, hinges, stitching and cracked joints. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 203)
    - Rents and Insurance, 1889-1892; Areas of board and spine edges and corners are worn and frayed. Spine is partially detached exposing crash, hinges, stitching and cracked joints. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 204)
      Inside Book Plate - Short and Forman, Cleveland, OH, No. 79440
    - Suspense Accounts, 1882-1883; Areas of board and spine edges and corners are worn and frayed. Spine is partially detached exposing crash, hinges, stitching and cracked joints. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 205)
    - JDR Accounts with Standard Oil Company, 1882-1884; Areas of board and spine edges and corners are worn and frayed. Spine is partially detached exposing crash, hinges, stitching and cracked joints. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 206)
    - JDR Accounts with Standard Oil Company, 1885-1886; Areas of board and spine edges and corners are worn and frayed. Spine is partially detached exposing crash, hinges, stitching and cracked joints. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 207)
    - JDR Accounts with Standard Oil Company, 1889-1892; Areas of board and spine edges and corners are worn and frayed. Spine is partially detached exposing crash, hinges, stitching and cracked joints. Paste downs and flyleafs' are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 208)
    - Margin Accounts, 1881-1883; Board and spine edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are cracking and separating along gutters. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 209)
    - JDR Accounts with Standard Oil Company (New York Office), 1881-1883; Board and spine edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are cracking and separating along gutters. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 210)
    - Analysis (Annual Breakdown of Expenses for New York Office, Personal Office, Taxes), 1920; Board and spine edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 211)
      Inside Book Plate - Goldsmith Bros., NY and National Column Book, No. 782
    - Analysis, 1921; Board and spine edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 212)
      Inside Book Plate - National Column Book, No. 782
    - Analysis, 1922; Board and spine edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 213)
    - Analysis, 1923; Board and spine edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs are intact and secure with missing front Flyleaf. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 214)
      Inside Book Plate - National Column Book, No. 782 and Royal Ribbon and Carbon Company, New York
    - Analysis, 1924; Board and spine edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 215)
      Inside Book Plate - Royal Ribbon and Carbon Company, New York, Standard Columnar Book, No. 23
    - Analysis, 1925; Board and spine edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 216)
      Inside Book Plate - Royal Ribbon and Carbon Company, New York, No. 123
    - Analysis, 1926-1927; Board and spine edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs are intact and secure with front Flyleaf partially detached from hinge. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 217)
      Inside Book Plate - Vernon Columnar Book, No. 51
    - Analysis, 1928-1930; Board and spine edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 218)
    - Analysis, 1928-1931; Spine is detached from joints. Board and spine edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 219)
    - Analysis, 1932-1933; Spine is detached from joint and board. Board edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 220)
      Inside Book Plate - Standard Columnar Book, No. 23
    - Analysis, 1934-1935; Spine is detached. Board edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 221)
    - Analysis, 1934-1936; Spine is missing. Board edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 222)
    - Analysis, 1936; Board and spine edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 223)
    - Analysis, 1936-1937; Spine is missing. Board edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 224)
    - Analysis, 1937-1938; Spine is detached. Board edges and corners are slightly worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 225)
    - Expense Account, Forest Hill, 1905-1907; Spine is worn, frayed, partially exposing crash, and cracking along joints. Board edges and corners are worn, frayed and missing pieces. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 226)
      Inside Book Plate - Albers Bros., New York, No. 2480
    - Expense Account, Forest Hill, 1911-1914; Spine is worn, frayed, partially exposing crash, and cracking along joints. Board edges and corners are worn, frayed and missing pieces. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 227)
    - Expense Account, Forest Hill, No. 1, 1915-1916; Spine is worn, frayed and cracking along joints. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 228)
      Inside Book Plate - Edward V. Brokaw and Bro., New York, No. 11399
    - Expense Account, Golf, No. 1, 1915-1916; Spine is worn, frayed and cracking along joints. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 229)
      Inside Book Plate - Edward V. Brokaw and Bro., New York, No. 11398
    - Expense Account, New York, No. 1, 1915-1916; Spine is worn, frayed and cracking along joints. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 230)
      Inside Book Plate - Edward V. Brokaw and Bro., New York, No. 11400
    - Expense Account, Pocantico Hills, No. 1, 1915-1916; Spine is detached, worn and frayed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 231)
      Inside Book Plate - Edward V. Brokaw and Bro., New York, No. 11461
    - Expense Account, Pocantico Hills, No. 2, 1905-1908; Spine is worn, frayed and cracking along joints with areas of the crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 232)
    - Expense Account, JDR, 1916; Spine is detached with areas of the crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed with missing pieces. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 233)
    - Payroll, 1919; Spine is missing with crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed with missing pieces. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 234)
      Inside Book Plate - National Columnar Book, No. 788
    - Payroll, 1918-1920; Pages are yellowing. Entries are typescript. (Box 235)
      Payroll for personal salaries, housekeepers, chauffeurs
    - Payroll, 1921; Pages are yellowing. Entries are typescript. (Box 236)
    - Payroll, 1922; Pages are yellowing. Entries are typescript. (Box 237)
    - Contracts, Betterments, Additions, No. 1, 1915-1916; Spine is worn, frayed and cracking along joints. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 238)
      Inside Book Plate - Edward V. Brokaw and Bro., New York, No. 11561
    - H. M. Sinclair Account, Forest Hill, 1883; Board and spine edges are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 239)
    - H. M. Sinclair Account, Forest Hill, 1883; Board and spine edges are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 239)
    - Donations, No. 1, 1915-1916; Spine is worn, frayed and cracking along joints. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 240)
      Inside Book Plate - Edward V. Brokaw and Bro., New York, No. 11460
    - General and Office Expenses, No. 1, 1915-1916; Spine is detached from joints, worn, frayed with spine piece and crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 241)
      Inside Book Plate - Edward V. Brokaw and Bro., New York, No. 11397
    - Expense Book, 1915-1917; Location Unknown (Box 242)
    - Expense Book, 1917-1918; Spine is detached from joints, worn, frayed with spine piece and crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 243)
    - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Ledger, 1916-1925; Spine is worn, frayed, cracking along joints, with spine piece and crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 244)
      Inside Book Plate - Edward V. Brokaw and Bro., New York
    - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Ledger, 1926-1928; Spine is worn and frayed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 245)
    - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Cash Journal and Trial Balance, 1920-1924; Spine is worn and frayed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 246)
    - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (LSRM) - Appropriations Book, 1922 June-1925 March (Box 247)
      Inside Book Plate - Moore's Loose Leaf Binders, Rochester, NY
    - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (LSRM) - Appropriations Book, No. 1, 1918 December-1922 February (Box 248)
    - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (LSRM) - Appropriations Book, No. 2, 1922 February-1924 February (Box 249)
    - Lucy M. Spelman - Ledger, 1907-1917; Spine is worn, frayed, cracking along joints, with spine piece and crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 250)
    - Lucy M. Spelman - Ledger, 1918-1920; Spine is worn, frayed, cracking along joints, with spine piece and crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 251)
    - Lucy M. Spelman - Journal, 1907-1917; Spine is worn, frayed, cracking along joints, with spine piece and crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 252)
    - Lucy M. Spelman - Journal, 1918-1920; Spine is worn, frayed, cracking along joints, with spine piece and crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 253)
    - Lucy M. Spelman - Securities, No. 2, 1917; Spine is worn, frayed, cracking along joints, with spine piece and crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 254)
    - Laura Spelman Rockefeller - Ledger, 1907-1915; Spine is worn, frayed, cracking along joints, with spine piece and crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 255)
    - Laura Spelman Rockefeller - Journal, 1907-1914; Spine is missing with spine piece and crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 256)
    - Laura Spelman Rockefeller - Estate Cash Book, 1927-1932; Spine is worn, frayed, cracking along joints. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 257)
    - Lake Superior Consolidated Mines - 1894 Season, Spine is missing with spine piece and crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 258)
      Inside Book Plate - Standard Oil Company, New York, No. 20451
    - Penokee and Gogebic Consolidated Mines - Ledger No. 1, 1891-1892 November; Spine is worn and frayed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 259)
      Inside Book Plate - Short and Forman, Cleveland, OH, No. A33159
    - Penokee and Gogebic Consolidated Mines - Ledger No. 2, 1892 November-1894; Spine is worn and frayed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 260)
      Inside Book Plate - The Munhall Bro. Co., No. 2446
    - Penokee and Gogebic Consolidated Mines - Journal No. 1, 1891-1895; Spine is worn and frayed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 261)
    - Duluth, Missabe and Northern Railway, Co. - Ledger, 1897; Location Unknown (Box 262)
    - Davison Fund, Inc. - Pledge Sheets, 1921-1931; Location Unknown (Box 263)
    - Equitable Trust, 1915-1917; Spine is missing. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 264)
      Inside Book Plate - Brown Green Co., NY, No. S33031
    - Cash Index Ledger, 1893-1901; Spine is worn, frayed, cracked along joints, with crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 265)
      Inside Book Plate - Burr's Record Index, Hartford, CT
    - Pledge Sheets Book, 1921-1931 (Box 266)
      Inside Book Plate - Edward V. Brokaw and Bro., New York, No. 86561
    - Index, Checks, No. 20-300, 1919-1921; Spine is missing with crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are separated from eachother. Pages and gutters are separating from stitching. (Box 267)
      Inside Book Plate - Burr's Combination Index, Hartford, CT, No. 15116, Year 1898
    - Index, Checks, No. 1207-8300, 1919-1921; Spine is worn, frayed and cracked along joints with crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 268)
      Inside Book Plate - Burr's Combination Index, Hartford, CT, Copyrighted 1883
    - William Rockefeller Letterbooks, 1898; Spine is worn, frayed and cracked along joints with crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 269)
    - William Rockefeller Letterbooks, 1898 January 20-1899 July 11; Spine is missing with crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 270)
      Inside Book Plate - H. C. Davison and Co., New York, No. 505
    - William Rockefeller Letterbooks, 1900 May 31-1901 April 12; Spine is missing with crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 271)
    - William Rockefeller Letterbooks, 1901 April 13-1902 March 22; Spine is missing with crash exposed. Board edges and corners are worn and frayed. Paste Downs and Flyleaf's are intact and secure. Pages and gutters are intact and secure. (Box 272)
  - Trial Balances, 1875-1915; F.2
    - Trial Balances, 1875-1897 (Box 1)
    - Trial Balances, 1890-1915 (Box 2)
  - Charities Index Cards, 1863-1903; FV14
    The index cards in this subseries are arranged alphabetically by beneficiary.
    John D. Rockefeller was a meticulous bookkeeper who kept careful track of the money he spent, invested, loaned, and was owed. His numerous ledgers and account books and the voluminous correspondence generated on his behalf amply illustrate his practice of careful record-keeping.
    Rockefeller also kept careful track of the money that he gave away to friends, relatives, strangers, churches, and other charitable purposes. One aspect of his record-keeping with respect to his charity was his system of noting his gifts on index cards. Rockefeller apparently began to keep this index of his charitable gifts sometime in the early or mid 1880s, but he went back through his ledgers to add select earlier gifts from as far back as 1863. At the top of each card, Rockefeller listed the name of the individual or organization for which the gift was intended; below it he recorded the date and the amount of each gift, along with the name of the individual to whom it was sent. Occasionally his list of gifts to a particular beneficiary would fill the card and he would begin a second card; gifts to several of Rockefeller's beneficiaries required more than two cards.